<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Boldly Going Nowhere</title>
    <link>https://martynrees.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Boldly Going Nowhere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:44:12 +0930</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martynrees.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Wifi 6E</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/2023/06/introducing-wifi-6e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:44:12 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/2023/06/introducing-wifi-6e/</guid>
      <description>Because marketing people like to make things confusing, we have Wifi 6, and now Wifi 6E. So what is the difference?
Both are based on the 802.11ax standard, so no difference there.
What 6E does is introduces support for the 6Ghz frequency, which means more channels, less CCI, and the ability to deploy wider channel widths.
Like the 5ghz specturm though, different countries have allowed different parts of the spectrum to be available for 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.11 Roaming</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/2022/10/802.11-roaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 16:28:49 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/2022/10/802.11-roaming/</guid>
      <description>What is 802.11r roaming and why is is so important to users (and you)? Wireless roaming is an essential feature for any wireless network, especially for those that are deployed in large, multi-building environments such as universities, hospitals, and campus networks. A simplified explanation is that &amp;ldquo;802.11 roaming refers to the process by which a wireless client device seamlessly transitions between different access points (APs) or base stations within a wireless network while maintaining an uninterrupted connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zigbee</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/2022/07/zigbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 16:36:25 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/2022/07/zigbee/</guid>
      <description>Having had zigbee in the home for a couple of years, and getting more and more devices spread across the home, I figured it was time to understand a little more about the protocol, and also work toward my CWISA certification.
Zigbee is a wireless networking protocol that is primarily used for low-power, low-data rate applications in the Internet of Things (IoT). Zigbee falls under the IEEE 802.11.15.4 specification, which covers a suite of high level communications protocls for creating personal area networks (PAN&amp;rsquo;s) via low power digitial radios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUCM Convert LDAP to LDAPS</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/2020/02/cucm-convert-ldap-to-ldaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 09:38:21 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/2020/02/cucm-convert-ldap-to-ldaps/</guid>
      <description>This post is applicable for both CUCM and Unity Connection, but for simplicity sake we will just cover CUCM here. The process of uploading and converting Unity Connection is the same. This process is also the same no matter which version of CUCM/Unity connection.
Cisco have released the following field notice that covers upcoming changes to connections between CUCM/unityCx and LDAP servers for syncronising and authenticating users.
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/voice_ip_comm/cucm/trouble/12_5_1/fieldNotice/cucm_b_fn-secure-ldap-mandatory-ad.html
The short of it is that Microsoft are enforcing that connections should now be over SSL rather than unencrypted transport methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome Revoked Self Signed Certificates</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/2020/01/google-chrome-revoked-self-signed-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 10:25:14 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/2020/01/google-chrome-revoked-self-signed-certificates/</guid>
      <description>Google Chrome can block you from getting to your lab devices (like your WLC) or other devices that have self signed certicates. If you get an error like this, and you can&amp;rsquo;t get past, then there is still a way without having to buy a signed cert!
To get around this click somewhere on the page and then type thisisunsafe
Then like magic Chrome will load the page!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CWNP Certification Program</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/2019/08/cwnp-certification-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 10:19:48 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/2019/08/cwnp-certification-program/</guid>
      <description>This post is more about finding where to start with the CWNP program, rather than focussing on any particular exam or level of knowledge.
The CWNP certification program is vendor neutral, and is seen to be the best way to learn about wireless without any specific vendors terms or proprietary information being thrown at you, and best of all you don&amp;rsquo;t have to remember any menu structure or config file structure for the exams&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating a Self Signed Certificate on Windows Server</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/2019/07/generating-a-self-signed-certificate-on-windows-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:04:17 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/2019/07/generating-a-self-signed-certificate-on-windows-server/</guid>
      <description>When configuring a Windows server with the NPS Role in order to authenticate wireless clients using PEAP (Protected EAP), you may need to generate a temporary self signed certificate in order to complete testing, or finish the configuration. Configuring the NPS server for PEAP authentication is outside of the scope of this post, and may be covered in a future post, but this will at least allow you to generate a Certificate in order to get the services running and testing completed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
