<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Wireless on Boldly Going Nowhere</title>
    <link>https://martynrees.github.io/tags/wireless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wireless on Boldly Going Nowhere</description>
    <image>
      <title>Boldly Going Nowhere</title>
      <url>https://martynrees.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:44:12 +0930</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://martynrees.github.io/tags/wireless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Wifi 6E</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/post/introducing_6e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:44:12 +0930</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/post/introducing_6e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because marketing people like to make things confusing, we have Wifi 6, and now Wifi 6E. So what is the difference?&lt;br /&gt;
Both are based on the 802.11ax standard, so no difference there.&lt;br /&gt;
What 6E does is introduce support for the 6GHz frequency, which means more channels, less CCI, and the ability to deploy wider channel widths.&lt;br /&gt;
Like the 5GHz spectrum though, different countries have allowed different parts of the spectrum to be available for 802.11 use, and like 2.4GHz and 5GHz, this is unlicensed spectrum*. Another thing to note is that currently 6E is only approved for indoor use.&lt;br /&gt;
Let&amp;rsquo;s break down what 6E actually introduces:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>802.11 Roaming</title>
      <link>https://martynrees.github.io/post/80211-roaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 16:28:49 +1030</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martynrees.github.io/post/80211-roaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is 802.11r roaming and why is is so important to users (and you)?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Wireless roaming is an essential feature for any wireless network, especially for those that are deployed in large, multi-building environments such as universities, hospitals, and campus networks. A simplified explanation is that &amp;ldquo;802.11 roaming refers to the process by which a wireless client device seamlessly transitions between different access points (APs) or base stations within a wireless network while maintaining an uninterrupted connection. Roaming is crucial for mobile devices, such as smartphones, laptops, or tablets, as they move within the coverage area of a Wi-Fi network.&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;
The reality is that acheiving this is a hell of a lot harder! BUT we have some standards and nerd knobs that help us to make it a little bit easier. &lt;br /&gt;
These include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
